# CARLEIAL FERNANDES, SAMUEL

DOCTOR OF NATURAL SCIENCES



## Current position

2017 – now (Post Doc) Research Assistant at the Prof. Elbert AG, University of Konstanz Project: Narrative Exposure Therapy for traumatized offenders in North Kivu Project: Effect of Narrative Exposure Therapy versus treatment as usual in a sample of trauma survivors who live under ongoing threat:

a randomized controlled trial in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

#### Education

1991 – 1994	Primary school, Instituto Educacional de Alencar, Brazil
1995 – 1998	Primary school, Colégio 7 de Setembro, Brazil
1999 – 2001	Secondary school, Colégio 7 de Setembro, Brazil

### Graduate and post-graduate studies

2002 – 2006	BSc. in Biological Sciences at the Federal University of Ceará (UFC, Brazil)
	Supervisor: Dr. Christian Westerkamp
	Short thesis title: Por quê o nectário é tão grande e oblíquo em oiticica?
2008 - 2010	MSc. in Biological Sciences at the National Autonomous University of Mexico
	Supervisor: Dr. Alfonso Delgado-Salinas
	Short thesis title: Biología floral de Aeschynomene amorphoides
2013 – 2017	PhD in Biological Sciences (Dr. rer. nat.) at the University of Konstanz
	associated with The Max Planck Research School (IMPRS) for Organismal Biology
	Supervisors: Dr. Marc Stift and Dr. Mark van Kleunen
	Thesis title: The early steps of plant mating system evolution

## Research experience

2002 – 2006	Volunteer at the Plant Anatomy and Morphology Lab, UFC, Brazil
2011 – 2011	Technical support researcher at the RON Herbarium, UNIR, Brazil
	Project: Integration, qualification and provision of data related to botanical
	collections in the Brazilian Amazon (REFLORA/CNPq)
2015 – 2016	Volunteer at HONKO Mangrove Conservation & Education, Madagascar
	Project: Mangrove long-term monitoring and sustainable livelihoods (2 weeks)

### Teaching experience

2005 – 2006	Teaching assistant, "Plant anatomy and morphology" course, UFC, Brazil
2011 – 2011	Assistant professor at distance education, "Biology" studies, UNIR, Brazil
2015 – 2016	Teaching assistant, "Plant physiology" compact course, University of Konstanz

#### Languages

Portuguese (native)

English (TOEFL: 102/120, in 2011)

German (Goethe Institut: B2.2, in 2013) Spanish (EPLE/UNAM: 830/1000, in 2008)

#### **Awards & Grants**

2005 – 2006	stipend for Bachelor's degree funding (PIBIC/UFC; 300 R\$/month)
2008 - 2010	stipend for Master's degree funding (CONACYT; 7,000 MXN/month)
2013 – 2017	stipend plus research and travel expenses for funding of PhD (1,365 €/month)
2014	best oral presentation, PopBio Meeting
2018	Independent Research Grant, Zukunftskolleg, University of Konstanz ( <b>4,740 €</b> )
2019	Young Scholar Fund, University of Konstanz (6,330 €)

#### **Publication list**

Carleial S & Bigio NC (2014) What survived from the PLANAFLORO Project: Angiosperms of Rondônia State, Brazil, Checklist, 10(1): 33-45

Carleial S, Delgado-Salinas A, Domínguez CA & Terrazas T (2015) Reflexed flowers in Aeschynomene amorphoides (Fabaceae: Faboideae): a mechanism promoting pollination specialization? *Bot J Linn Soc*, 177(4): 657-666

**Tedder A, Carleial S, Golebiewska M, Kappel C, Shimizu KK & Stift M (2015)** Evolution of the selfing syndrome in Arabis alpina (Brassicaceae), *PloS ONE*, 10(6): e0126618

**Carleial S, van Kleunen M & Stiff M (2017)** Small reductions in corolla size and pollen:ovule ratio, but no changes in flower shape in selfing populations of the North American Arabidopsis lyrata, *Oecologia*, 183: 401-413

**Carleial S, van Kleunen M & Stiff M (2017)** Relatively weak inbreeding depression in selfing but also outcrossing populations of North American Arabidopsis lyrata, *J Evol Biol*, 30:1994-2004

Carleial S, Maurel N, van Kleunen M & Stiff M (2018) Oviposition by the Mountain Alcon Blue butterfly increases with host plant flower number and host ant abundance. Basic Appl Ecol, 28:87-96

**Robjant K, Koebach A, Schmitt S, Chibashimba A, Carleial S & Elbert T (2019)** The treatment of posttraumatic stress symptoms and aggression in female former child soldiers using adapted Narrative Exposure therapy – a RCT in eastern democratic republic of Congo. *Behavior Res Ther*, 123:103482

**Robjant K, Schmitt S, Chibashimba A, Carleial S, Elbert T & Koebach A (2020)** Trauma, aggression and post conflict perpetration of community violence in female former child soldiers – a study in Eastern DR Congo. Front Psychiatry Accepted